Haejin Kim

(805) 252-6937 | haejin kim@bren.ucsb.edu | Webpage | GitHub | LinkedIn | Santa Barbara, CA

PROFILE STATEMENT

With over seven years of experience in data analysis and project management in Hankook tire, I developed the development of a comprehensive portfolio project monitoring system utilizing SQL. Leveraging this system, I crafted a predictive cost model for future projections. Additionally, I possess proficiency in Tableau, utilizing it to generate analytical reports for board documentation during my tenure at the Green Climate Fund.

EDUCATION

Master of Environmental Data Science (6/2024)

Bren School of Environmental Science & Management – University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB)

<u>Highlighted Coursework</u>: Statistics for Environmental Data Science, Geospatial Analysis & Remote Sensing, Databases and Data Management, Machine Learning in Environmental Science, Data Cleaning, Text Analyst, Carbon Counting

<u>Highlighted Project</u>: Assessing the Impact of Supply-Side Policies on Oil Extraction, Emissions, Health, and Employment in California (SB 1137)

Bachelor of Science in Material Science and Engineering (12/2012) Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

<u>Highlighted Project</u>: Sol-Gel Synthesis and Testing of Li_{1+x}NiMg_xO_{2(1+x)} Cathode Material for Li Ion Batteries

Master of Science in Sustainability Science (Withdraw, 06/2022)

Columbia University, Ithaca, NY

Highlighted Coursework: Climate Change Law and Policy in Columbia Law School

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hankook Tire, Seoul, Korea (1/2014-6/2021)

Project Management and Data Analyst (8/2016–6/2021)

- Developed a new real-time portfolio monitoring system using SQL, continuously refining portfolio data to improve data quality and accuracy.
- Created a predictive cost model for future profit by leveraging forecasting data of raw materials, technology development, and sales data through SQL.
- Conducted bi-weekly reporting of updated or new projects to the head manager and facilitated dissemination of decisions to relevant colleagues.

Entry Material Research and Development Manager (1/2014–7/2016)

- Nurtured ongoing relationships with vendors (entities) and worked to minimize issues.
- Monitored all aspects of vendor work and ensured that contract deadlines were met and resolved vendor (entities) disputes in a timely and professional manner.

Green Climate Fund (GCF), Songdo, Korea (7/2022–7/2023)

Intern (Pipeline Management), Division of Mitigation and Adaptation (1/2023-7/2023)

- Coordinated and updated timelines for adjusting pre-approval pipeline projects, liaising with other divisions prior to board meetings.
- Assisted in collecting, verifying, analyzing, and disseminating data for reports, presentations, and other knowledge products related to project pipeline management.
- Regularly monitored IPMS and proposed new data collection workflows as needed.
- Provided analytical support for publications for the 34 and 35th board meeting using Tableau.
- Reviewed the concept note, aligned with the GCF's objectives, policies and investment criteria as Secretariat.

Intern (Accreditation Entity and Relation Unit), Division of Country Program (7/2022–12/2022)

- Reviewed entity applications and participated in the accreditation process.
- Supported the 33rd board meeting and facilitated communication with entities and other divisions.

World Wildlife Fund (WWF), Seoul, Korea

Senior Officer, Climate & Energy Team (7/2021–12/2021)

- Collaborated with WWF partners, primarily initiated in environmental projects.
- Supported to understand SBTi and TCFD for electronic and insurance company to join this program for climate action and derive the RE100.
- Supported in organizing the Climate Action Conference, including inviting guests and benefactors, and working with event agencies.
- Composed and delivered the WWF statement for COP26 to four Korean government departments, including the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Environment, Finance, and Economy

SKILLS AND ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Languages: Korean (native), Japanese (JLPT 3N)

Computer Skill: Python, R, Q/ArcGIS, MATLAB, C++, MS Office, SQL (SAP ERP system), Tableau, GitHub